# Sahan Panangamu

Cheltenham, Gloucestershire | 07367 167 279 | jsahan.lakmal@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sahan/panangamu/

#### **PROFILE**

A highly motivated software tester / QA Engineer with extensive experience working on projects across a breadth of sectors. Strong background in manual and automated testing of applications across various domains, with a hands-on approach to working with business / technical teams to elicit requirements and execute testing plans appropriately. Well versed in supporting projects through full lifecycles to meet all core aims and objectives successfully in line with expectations.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, SQL, Selenium
- Tools & IDEs: Visual Studio, JMeter, XMind, Eclipse, UFT, SAP, Jenkins, Appium, Playwright
- Testing types: Automation testing, Manual testing, Performance testing, Regression testing, API testing
- Databases: MSSQL Server, MySQL
- Version control: GitHub, GitLab
- CI/CD: Azure DevOps
- Project Management Tools: Atlassian JIRA
- Processes: Agile, Scrum, STLC, SDLC
- Functional & Non-Technical: Team lead, quick learning, Time management, critical thinking, test planning, estimation, scheduling, release management, defect management, creating and executing test scripts

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**QA Engineer** Jul 2021 – Oct 2022

CAMMS Asia

- Revamped and optimised the test automation framework to enhance efficiency and reliability.
- Managed bug tracking and communication, fostering effective team collaboration.
- Contributed insights to release planning and reviews for successful project outcomes.
- Led the Incident team, managing QA aspects for swift incident resolutions, and actively participated in agile ceremonies, offering valuable contributions to the test discipline.
- Working on all aspects of regression testing, unit testing and performance testing on various web applications.
- Supporting the creation of testing plans, test cases and test approach documents, and driving the deployment of QA frameworks for manual / automated functional and non-functional testing activities.
- Deploying automated test scripts for improve testing efficiency and reduce manual testing efforts.
- Tracking testing progress, ensuring accuracy and quality standards are maintained through to solution releases.
- Executing testing in line with requirements and following up on defects for resolution with development teams.
- Participating in overall release management processes and validating application readiness for production deployment as well as adherence to compliance standards.
- Implementing comprehensive QA strategies and test plans for software projects which have resulted in a 20% reduction in product defects and improved overall client satisfaction.

CAMMS Asia

- Conducted comprehensive testing, including functional, GUI, regression, smoke, and performance testing, by meticulously
  analysing user stories and crafting detailed test cases.
- Facilitated defect resolution by reporting, analysing, and validating modifications to specifications, ensuring seamless alignment with project requirements.
- Spearheaded the release of framework updates across the entire organization, enhancing efficiency and aligning systems with the latest advancements.
- Provided valuable insights during Sprint Review and Retrospective meetings at the conclusion of each sprint, contributing to continuous improvement and informed decision-making.
- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to uphold quality standards, ensuring client satisfaction, and fostering a
  collaborative working environment.
- Offered technical support to the team, addressing and resolving issues promptly, and engaged with senior management to make well-informed decisions, ensuring successful project deliveries.

### **Automation Associate Specialist QA**

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019

Virtusa Pvt Ltd

- Designed/Developed automation test scripts and executed automation scripts.
- Identified and Escalate risk issues.
- Requirement understanding and clarification through Q&A document.
- Played a leadership role and guided the team to achieve goals.
- Handling calls with overseas Manual Team.
- Participated in daily onsite/ offshore sync-up calls and team meetings.
- Provided more innovative ideas and implemented those with proper approvals Translate requirements to test cases for the wider team.

## Hardware & Network Technician

Jan 2014 - Sep 2015 & Nov 2019 - Aug 2020

Extreme Computer Technologies Pvt Ltd

## **EDUCATION**

### **MSc Information technology**

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

University of the West of England

## BSc (Hons.) Information technology

Jan 2016 - Dec 2019

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology

### PROFESSIONAL TRAINING & COURSES

- Introduction to cybersecurity Cisco
- Software testing foundations: test techniques LinkedIn
- Postman essential training LinkedIn
- Learning Microsoft 365 copilot LinkedIn

Portfolio - https://sahanpanangamu.netlify.app/

References available upon request.